Welcome back. In this part, we are going
to be making the icing. Yes, the
exciting icing for our donut. Um, and my
apologies. I did say in the last part we
were going to do the texturing and
lighting and stuff, but I just realized
like we should do we should finish the
modeling cuz we just modeled this thing.
So, let's finish focusing on modeling
before we jump to uh another concept.
So, we're going to do some icing. Yay.
Um, but first, we do have quite a lot of
objects going on in our scene. We got a
camera lamp. We got an object, an image
and stuff. We should try to organize
some things. And some of you might have
noticed in the top right hand corner,
you've got a list of all of your
objects, right? This is called your
outliner. Um, and it is a like a
spreadsheet version of all the objects
that are in your scene. And uh we're
going to use it later on to like
organize like create collections so it's
like easier to see and organize things.
But the first thing we need to do is
just add names to things that make
sense. Um, so for example, our mug here
is currently called cylinder. So if we
had a big scene with lots of objects
going on, we can't find it. So it's a
good habit to name your objects. So
there's a number of different ways you
can name something. Um, one is you can
just double click it in the outliner,
right? You can see now I can type in a
name like mug. Uh, you can also in your
3D viewport, you can hit F2, which is
the same hotkey in uh like Windows, I
don't know, maybe Mac, but for renaming.
Um, and then I can just type in a name
like donut. Um, and you can also do that
in uh the outliner as well. You can just
hit F2 and that'll also um also do the
renaming. So there we go. So now we got
names that actually make sense. Um, I
don't actually need the image anymore
even though I just renamed it. So I'm
just going to delete that. All right. So
we've now just got a camera, we got a
donut, a light, and a mug. Great. So
let's make that icing. I'm going to move
my mug out of the way. So G and then X.
So, I'm just going to throw it to the
side so we don't see it anymore. And
let's focus on our doughut. So, we want
to make some icing. And when it comes to
something as challenging as icing and
and really anything that there's so many
different ways to make things in 3D, and
every single method has a pro and a con.
So, for example, there is a fluid
simulator in Blender. It's not very
good. Um, but it exists and it is a way
you could create icing. You could
actually like create an object and then
simulate it falling and splatting over
it. The reason we're not going to do
that though is that one, it's incredibly
[snorts] complicated. There's so many
things that can go wrong with the
simulation. Blender Simulator is not
very good. Um, and then also you don't
have any control over the final result.
You have to keep re-aking things. It's
it's horrible. But there is another way
and that is to just do it by hand. And
at first that seems slower, but you have
much more control over it and it's
actually pretty easy to do. So I'm going
to show you how to do that. And it's
also a great way to introduce some more
tools and things and get you familiar
with different areas of Blender. So
icing follows the shape of the thing
that it's on. So really icing is
basically the shape that we've got. It's
basically half of this doughut. So if we
got half the doughut, we're halfway
there. Then we just need to add some
variation to it to make it look like
icing. So what I'm going to do is
duplicate my donut. So shift D. That is
how you duplicate. Uh you can also just
go object and then say duplicate objects
there. Shift D. Um and when you do this,
you are in the duplicated state and it's
saying now where do you want to place
that thing? Um and we don't want to
place it anywhere. We want to leave it
exactly where it was. And so I'm going
to hit escape. Now when you do that, it
hasn't um cancelled the duplication cuz
you can see at the top there we've now
got donut and then donut. 001. So there
is two objects still there. They're just
exactly in the exact same spot fighting
for space. Something you actually never
want to have is two objects sharing the
exact same space cuz then when a camera
moves or something happens uh in an
animation you see like flickering. Um
really really bad. Anyways, um I'm going
to double click that and I'm going to
call it icing just so that I can uh
quickly tell the two apart. [snorts] And
I want to delete the bottom half of my
doughut. So I'm going to go into front
view mode like that. And I need to uh go
into edit mode next. And I want to
select the bottom half of my donut. Um
this is face select. Current. Let's go
verticy select. Okay. And if I was to
click and then just drag over the bottom
half of my doughut, it would appear as
though as we have got half the doughut.
However, and this is an area of blender
that is not clear uh until you run into
problems. But if I was to change my
orbit, you can see it hasn't actually
selected half the donut. It's only
selected what it could see from that
view. So you have to turn on toggle
X-ray first or go into wireframe mode.
Um but uh yeah, you have to turn that on
first, then do your selection. And now
it will actually select all the way
through an object to the other side as
well. By the way, if you find that you
can't do this this drag selection that
I've got, if you've got instead a circle
over your cursor like like what I have
here, um what that means is you have
tapped the W key by mistake, which will
cycle through in the top little uh side
of your screen there. Um different
selection modes. I wish it was not W.
That's one of my complaints I've made to
the Blender team. W is so close to the
other keys you need on your keyboard. So
many people hit this, they hit the wrong
key and then they're in this thing and
then like nothing nothing works. So like
yeah, you want to be in this mode most
of the time. Um but yeah, you can change
to these other modes if you wanted to,
you know, do a special selection or
something as well. But anyways, that is
how to to fix that. And also just to to
call it out as well, we're going to be
doing some like stuff with this icing
that's going to maybe mess some things
up and you might run into some issues. I
got to call it out again. I've got an
unstuck yourself guide, troubleshooting
guide for just this tutorial. It is
free. Just click the link below um and
it'll take you there. Um because I want
you guys to be able to get through this
tutorial, but there's so many little
things that you could experience in
this. So um we're going to add it to
that guide um to try and help you. And
if you can't find um the answer to your
your problem in there, um hit up the
Discord. Uh the link for that is also um
in it. So I'll link to my website and
all the links will be there. So check
that out um if you run into issues. All
right. So, I've got the bottom half of
my donut. We have to delete it. So, I'm
going to hit X. When you do this, it's
saying which part of it you want to
delete. Now, this is one of those cases
where it actually matters like which one
of these you select cuz if you were to
select vertices, cuz it would appear as
though that's what you need to delete.
But if you did that, you'll notice
you've got now less than half because
along with the vertices selected is that
final line that is cut through the
middle there. So, I don't want to delete
that final line. and I want to delete
the other stuff. So, in my options here,
I've got an option for faces, which if
we try that, you can see is the solution
because when you uh deleting the faces,
you're only deleting what are like what
is a whole face, but these individual
points here don't make up a whole face.
This part does, so that's left behind,
but all the other stuff was deleted. So,
anyways, we should now have half of a
donut. So, I'm going to turn off toggle
X-ray now so I can see it. And if we
clicked off, you'll see that it actually
just looks exactly like a donut because
again, they're sharing the exact same
space. I do know it's there if I select
it in the uh little outliner there, but
it's uh completely invisible. So, the
first thing I want to do is I want to
add some thickness to this icing. And
this is something you should know how to
do. You should know it. If you don't
know it, you've not been paying
attention. Um but if you go to your
modifiers, there is a modifier. Another
clue. uh it is of course the solidify
modifier which adds thickness to any
face. So now that we've added that you
think something's broken, it's not
working. It is working. It's just that
by default the solidify will uh add
thickness inside. So if you change this
offset here to be the inverted, which is
one, it will now add the thickness the
other way, which is what we need. Okay,
so that's great. But of course, it
doesn't look very good. There's a a
quote which uh I always repeat. Uh
imperfection is the digital perfection
because the reason this looks fake, it's
just perfectly straight. There's no way
to get a laser cut icing across a donut
like this unless you're using 3D
software. So, we need to add randomness
to this edge here in order for it to
look realistic to our eye. So, I need to
go into edit mode. And when we do that,
we can't see the mesh because we've got
our solidifier blocking our view. So,
I'm going to click this disable in
viewport just to hide it so that I can
see it. So, when I turn it back on, I I
know it's there, but just while I'm
editing it, in order to see it, I need
to be able to um have it turned off. So,
to add randomness, what I could do is I
could come in here and I could select
one point like this. I could hit G and I
could move it down. Okay? Then I could
get the point next to it and I could
move this one down and then this one.
And I could do this and do this and we
could put ourselves to sleep trying to
make this donut [laughter] look good and
it would it would take forever. Um, but
thankfully in 3D there are tools for
everything to make your life easier. And
so one such tool is at the top here,
your proportional editing tool. What
this does is now when I hit G,
it'll move everything at once. Um, no.
It what it will do is it will it will uh
move everything with a fall-off area
around it. The reason it's moving the
entire mesh with it is that the fall-off
is so big that it's actually outside of
our view at the moment. This was
actually something I I called out in my
uh usability talk at the Blender
conference last year. Um, we could do
better than this, but basically if you
zoom way out, you will see there is a
circle around it. Um, and that's how big
it is. So, what we need to do is whilst
we're in this move state is we need to
reduce that. And you do that by
scrolling down. Scroll down, down, down,
down, down. Oh, no, that was the wrong
direction. Scroll up. Sorry. Scroll up,
not down. And that will make it scroll.
Ed smaller. So, scroll up to make it
smaller. Scroll down to make it bigger.
I just completely brain farted. If you
don't have a scroll wheel, by the way,
and this is another thing to call out.
When you're in a move state like we are
right now, you can see along the bottom
of our screen, you've got a list and
that only appeared there when you're in
that state. When I when I turn it off,
all those options are gone. But whilst
I'm in this state, there's a bunch of
options there. And the keyboard shortcut
is actually right there. Page up and
page down. Okay, so that is how we can
increase or decrease. So again, if you
if you don't see the the circle, you
just have to keep holding page down or
scrolling up um until it goes uh down to
something that you can see basically.
Anyways, now that we are in that state,
I'm going to hit zed, okay, to grab uh
sorry. Yeah. So, whilst I'm doing I I
don't want to just like freehand do it
because if I if I pull it down like
this, if it like if I watch what
happens. If I do it on the edge here
like this, it appears as though it's
it's pulling it straight down, right?
And I do this and this. But actually, if
you looked at it, these would be
slightly skewed a little bit. Um, just
because of like we're working in 3D.
We're looking at things from a different
perspective. Sometimes things appear to
be going down, but they're actually at
like a slight angle. So, it helps to um
when you're moving something to think of
which axis it's going on. So, I want it
to go straight down. So, G and then zed.
And now I'm going to pull it down. Okay.
That was a lot of work just to do this
one little bit. I'm sorry. All right.
Okay. So, we've pulled it down.
Excellent. Um I'll do a little bit more
as well. I'll just do a little bit here.
I'll do a little bit here. You can like
[clears throat] play with the um the
amount the the fall-off
like so. You know, you can play with it.
All right, cool. Now, if we turn on our
solidifier modifier, we've got the
thickness back, and you can see we've
got some variation to uh to the donut
there. So, let's let's continue on here.
So, let's pull this like so. I don't
want to go too far cuz we're going to
add some some dribbles soon. Dribble
sounds gross, but you know the little
runoff droplets
that uh that's going to go down down the
donut
like so. Okay, that is pretty good. Now,
you can see it's like partly like
intersecting it. Um, and that's
obviously because we've got proportional
editing, so it's actually kind of moving
some of these ones that are up top and
pulling it down as well. It's fine with
the solidify modifier, but we're
actually going to end up fixing it when
we uh when we do the dribble anyway cuz
I'm going to introduce another modifier
that's going to fix this. Um but
anyways, let's do this. Let's do the
dribble part. So, I'm going to look for
an area. Yeah. Like let's go Yeah. And
here where this bit's like running down.
Um and I'm going to um I want to make
this like a dribble that goes down the
donut here. And currently I can't really
continue to pull this. Like I could I
could like get like a sharp point like
that, but that does not look very good,
right? We need more geometry
essentially. So you might remember the
hotkey. If we want to extrude something,
it is E. But I can't just extrude one
point like that. Okay? Because there's
no face there. There's nothing that's
actually going to be rendered if I just
pull one point down. So I need to select
two points. Okay? So two points like
this. If I hit E and then zed and then
pull down and then release. And then if
I bring back my solidify modifier, you
can see we've got more geometry. Doesn't
look very good though. Um, so let's add
in another modifier. The same one that
we used on the mug as well. It's the
subdivision surface modifier. [snorts]
Um, as I say, you use these all the
time. Use it for most objects probably
have a subdivision modifier cuz it's so
useful. Um, but one of the things it's
good for is it like besides adding
detail, it like smooths things out for
us. So that little hard little block
that we had there has now turned into a
smoothed droplet looking shape which is
exactly what we want. But look,
it has separated from the donut. Now in
previous tutorials um I actually did
like a thing that showed you how to like
use this but make it like snap onto the
donut and it got all complicated.
Everyone screwed up their mesh at this
point. Um you can do this by hand as
well. you can like come in here and like
try to pull this in piece by piece, but
it's actually not necessary because
there is a modifier that will just do it
for you. Um, so if you go to your add
modifier stack, and then go to deform,
and then you're looking for the one
called shrink wrap. And by the way,
again, if you can't find it, just go up
to here, type in shrink wrap, and you'll
also find it there. So shrink wrap, what
this is going to do, it's going to
shrink it onto a mesh. But you have to
define the mesh first in order to see it
because if you don't, it just has no
effect. Absolutely. That's what the red
is h showing you. It's not doing
anything. So your target um yeah, you
can actually like select it from the
drop down or what most people do, you
click the little eyropper and then you
select the object. Bam. All right, now
it's working. And now we've got some
serious Z fighting where the uh faces
are overlapping. And this is horrible.
You never want this. All right. So, you
will remember uh when I was talking
about the modifier that it works top to
bottom. So, essentially what we've done
is we've gone uh add thickness, then add
detail, and then shrink wrap all of that
thickness onto the donut itself. So,
what we need to do is change the order
of this um and not go halfway cuz that
also won't do anything. Um we need to go
all the way to the top so the shrink
wrap is happening first. So, it's
snapping it onto the mesh. Then, it's
adding the solidify modifier. Then,
underneath that, it's adding the subsurf
modifier. And we can actually increase
this, make it a level two for the
viewport. And you can see it just adds a
little bit um extra detail there. Okay.
Um and you can go even higher, of
course, but you know, you will get uh
eventually it'll just get so slow for
your computer and there's not really
going to be any point, but you can just
go to level two for now. Okay. So, uh,
to quickly show you as well what the
shrink wrap is actually doing. Um,
because it's really it's not that clear.
Um, but yeah, this is this is where it's
that little piece is overhanging and
then it's essentially looking for the
nearest point um to find this mesh
underneath it and then it is just
snapping it uh to that point. So, it's
it's pretty good. Like I can drag this
like pretty far down like but there is
an extent I can so I'm just doing
another extrusion on this point. So, as
I pull it down, you can see it like it
kind of loses it. There's a point where
it just won't find the mesh anymore. So,
there's a point like at which you should
start to pull things into the mesh. It's
not magic. It's not going to just
magically find it. So, if I just pull it
all the way out there, there's no way
it's going to be able to find it. So
there is uh a limit, but you can see
this is it does make our job a lot
easier because I can um I can pull it
down and I can start to make um you know
some some big dribbles along my mesh
here. And I don't have to really worry
that much about the uh the placement
because it's just going to automatically
snap itself to the donut. I just have to
make sure the dribbles are straight. Um,
and if you look at reference, which you
should be doing, um, I'll put some
reference on, um, my, uh, the link below
on my website, so you can have a look
and just kind of go through it. Um, but
yeah, usually when when like droplets
form, they kind of like the gravity kind
of like builds at a point and it kind of
like gets sucked from the top. And so
you end up with like this thin bit in
the middle and then this like globule,
which is a crazy word, um, at the bottom
there. But essentially, it just means
the piece at the bottom, I'm just going
to make a little bit thicker than the
pieces above it. Okay, so that's one,
but we should do more. So I'm going to
go around and I'm going to add more. Um,
and just repeat the same thing. Just do
an extrusion on these little points
there and just kind of drag it down. So,
let's do that because yeah, I remember
the first doughut that I ever made. Oh,
way way back in the day, making the
first doughut. Um, and I really like I I
did one little dribble going down it.
And then I always wanted to frame the
the camera so that it was looking at
that cuz that was the most interesting
part of the donut. And then I learned
like ah just exaggerate. Just add little
dribbles everywhere. That is a big part
of being an artist is you look at
reality and then you find the bits that
are actually pleasing and then you
exaggerate it. And that's what I'm
doing. So, you know, donuts typically
don't have this many dribbles, but it's
very pleasing. It just makes it look
very like gooey and like, oh, there's so
much icing. Um, and you can see, by the
way, I'm not doing the same shape also
everywhere. So, this is like a half one,
right? And I'm kind of looking for like
where I can add um some different
shapes. Why is that? There's a gap
there. Oh, okay. Oh, no. Yeah, I was uh
recording
uh for this this tutorial and I recorded
something and then I like reverted it.
But I've now got a giant face here where
there should be not a giant face there.
So, what do you do? You you've
accidentally got this thing. There is uh
and this is you obviously don't have to
do this because this is not your
problem. Um but I'm just going to use
the knife tool which is a way to do an
incision on a mesh and just add more
geometry like freehand. So I've just uh
fixed that little problem that I had
there. But uh you hopefully should not
have that problem. Um yeah, let's I'm
going to just pull this down. I'm going
to turn on proportional editing. I'm
going to add a little bit that's going
down. And let's select these two. Turn
off proportional. Let's add another
little bit that's going right here. Add
a little bit of variance. And let's add
Let's add another big one right here.
Pull this one down. But this is the fun
part, you know? I mean, aside from the
finicky like going like sideways,
looking at where it appears and then
straightening it. But you get to kind of
like shape things and just like with
your eye just just play with it. It's
actually one of the cool things of of
3D. Um, it's also why a lot of people
get into 3D is they want to do art, but
whenever they pick up a pencil, they
just can't get the lines where they want
it. And the great thing about 3D is is
that you've got points and you can move
those points after the fact. You're not
drawing freehand. So, if you there's no
case where you like screw up a line and
you have to like rub it out and try
again. Like, you just grab a point and
just kind of like move it around um like
I'm doing right now.
So, that's one of the uh one of the joys
of of 3D. I'm just trying to just doing
filler talk if you can't tell. Just grab
a few pieces, move them all down
together. Why not? There we go. That's
kind of interesting. I might add I might
just take this one at the bottom there
off. And I'll just maybe pull these out
just so we've got more variance that
goes all the way around it. But play
with it as much you want. Um, you know,
you can pause this and, you know, play
with it. Um, but I'm just trying to make
it look generally appealing. Now, one
way to improve this, you'll notice that
the icing is separating from it, right?
It's going uh it's going up right there.
And again, that's because of how subsurf
modifiers work. There's a point here and
there's a point here. So, it has to uh
it has to make this really rounded
shape. But real liquid when it is uh in
this state when it's clinging to an
object uh this part here as as it hits
it that part will be like solid right
and then the rest of it like this part
is round but then this part is like
hugging the actual surface. So
thankfully we can do that. There is a
setting in the solidifier setting
options which I might have to move.
There we go. So we can see it. Um,
underneath edge data, there is an option
here for a crease. Okay, so what a
crease is doing, we didn't really talk
about it with the mug, but it's
essentially on an edge, it's creasing it
and saying like instead of like doing
that huge rounded thing, just kind of
tighten it on that edge. Very similar to
adding the geometry like what we did on
the mug, but this is a way to do it
without adding extra geometry. It does
kind of add a little bit of stretching,
um, but it's not really that noticeable
on something like this. But that is very
very nice, very solid. Um, it's hugging
it and it looks very pleasing.
Excellent. Now, we could as well I
didn't actually do this for my final
one. Um, because I forgot. [laughter]
Um, but I I realized after I was like,
"Oh, yeah. I guess like the part that's
on the inside of the donut." Yeah, I I
forgot to do that. Um, but yeah, you can
also like do the exact same thing just
playing with it. If you find like it's
kind of hard to like look at it inside
the donut, if you just select the middle
row. So if you just hold down alt and
then select on that middle row, you can
use the same focus um button. So numpad
period or tilda and then view. And then
that will just lock it on to those
selected vertices. So that focus key
that I mentioned, it works on uh in edit
mode as well, which is good. So yeah, I
could just pull these down like this and
just, you know, the camera's not really
going to notice it. You just want to
make sure that it's, you know, not
perfectly straight like mine was in the
uh final render. Um it it doesn't really
like who's going to notice, you know,
who's going to tell really? Um annoying
people are going to point it out if the
inside part's too straight. All right.
So, that's pretty good. Um actually,
something I might do cuz I noticed like
looking from the top cuz this is where
the camera's going to be like we're not
really able to see much donut. like the
icing is a little bit too far down. So,
I'm just going to grab some of these
points here using proportional editing.
I'm just going to pull them up to just
expose a little bit more of the
underlying doughut, which is definitely
going to make the doughnut look a little
bit more handmade, you know? Um cuz like
obviously a probably a professional
donut from Crispy Cream or something
doesn't have this much variance in it,
but it's okay. It does kind of help it
give it a uh yeah, realistic kind of
look. Now, there's one thing that would
really improve the look of this icing,
and that is thickness variation. Because
if you go around it, you'll see that the
exact, you know, the distance from here
to here is the exact same thing as like,
you know, what it would be over here to
here. And that's just not the case.
We've got like icing that is dribbling
down. These little droplets are kind of
like breaking away. And what happens
when those droplets break and then they
kind of stop? They build up, right? So,
we should actually see these kind of
like swell a little bit. They should be
a little bit rounder at the heads of
each of these points. Also, along the
edges here, every little edge here
should be a little bit more inflated
than the rest of it. And although that
sounds like nothing, when you when you
do it, when you actually add this little
detail, it really does improve the
realism. So, we can't do that because
all we've got is these little points
here. Okay. So, just like what we did
with the mug, there comes a time where
you need to break the um break the uh
non-destructive workflow and apply your
modifiers. So, this shrink wrap here, by
the way, when you apply something, you
have to apply it in like top to bottom.
So, even really, although we really just
we only want to apply the solidify.
That's the main one we want to do. Um,
we have to first of all apply this the
shrink wrap because that's the one that
is first and that's the one like if we
if we applied this one first, we would
lose uh the the the shrink wrap would
have to go after and it would just yeah,
it would screw it up. So, we have to
apply the shrink wrap first. So, go here
and click apply. Okay. Now, in edit
mode, you can see we've still got those
single points, but they're now snapped
to the mesh. All right. But it means we
no longer have that automatic snapping.
So, if I was to pull these out, you can
see they're now separated from the mesh.
So, just keep that in mind. Um, we still
can't edit the mesh there because we
haven't applied the solidify. So, I'm
going to apply the solidify now. And now
we've got these points here. Okay. So,
now if I wanted to with just these
points, I could pull some of these
points out. Turning off proportional
editing. And I could just pull them out
a little bit. And that's better. But we
don't have enough detail here. We need
more geometry to play with in order to
add this extra detail. So, we need to
apply our subsurf modifier. So, I'm
going to on here I'm going to hit apply.
And actually, there's a hotkey if you
want to don't want to have to go to the
drop down each time. Ctrl A will apply
the selected uh modifier. And now in
edit mode, look at this. Now, we've got
all this extra geometry to play with.
So, now if I wanted to, I could turn on
proportional editing. I could select one
point. I could try and get a kind of a
shape like this. That would be probably
the best way to do it if I was
restricted to edit mode. And that'll get
me some of the way there. I could, you
know, pull individual points out. I
could try and do that. But you can see
it's it's very finicky. And it's really
it's not the tool to use because, like I
said, there are tools for everything in
3D to try to help you to um yeah, to to
to do things better. So, go to the top
of your screen. We're currently in
layout. That's all we've done so far.
We're going to swap to sculpting. All
right. Now, when you swap to a new one
of these views here, it'll uh it's
assuming the default view of Blender,
which is like when everything was like
10 m long or whatever. So, our donut is
tiny. So, we have to focus on the
selected object. So, I'm just going to
hit numpad period. Um, that hasn't
worked. [laughter] Okay, don't worry
about that. Um, all right.
[clears throat]
So, instead of in sculpt mode, change to
object mode. Then hit numpad period or
view selected and then now jump back to
sculpt mode. And now we're back to For
some reason I thought focus worked in uh
in sculpt mode. Yeah. All right.
Sometimes you just teach something and
then you go, "Oh, that never worked.
What was I talking about?" Anyway, um
okay. In sculpt mode now, and make sure
you're looking at the correct one, okay,
not the donut, but the icing itself. If
I was to now
draw over this, you can see we're
drawing into the mesh of the icing.
Isn't that cool? All right. So, what I
want to do is I want to change my brush
and I want to find the one brush which
is really going to help us here and it
is this one, the inflate deflate brush.
Now, your brush size here can be
controlled by the size at the top or
there is a hotkey F. And when you hit F,
you just choose with your mouse like how
big the size needs to be. Okay. So, I
can pull out. And then now, if I just
draw over that little gobuille there,
the end piece, it just adds a little bit
of inflation.
And I'm So, I'm just pulling it around
just slightly. I don't want to go too
far, but just adding these little
inflated points will really help this to
look realistic. The other thing is you
can actually shape some of the the mesh
as well. So, there's another brush that
I use all the time, which is the grab
brush. You just uh essentially just pull
mesh like that. So that's another easy
way to just kind of move pieces around
like so. You can just shape things like
this. Add a little bit of extra detail
if you want. Yeah.
And all is well.
So you can see I I'm doing a little bit
on the edge here again because all the
edges there should have a little bit of
buildup of the fluid because that's
where gravity kind of makes it stall and
like stop cuz it just kind of like runs
out of um like the the tension will be
more than the gravity that's pulling it
down. Um you get the idea. Anyways, play
with that as much as you like.
But of course we have some homework to
finish off this video. So, what I want
you to make is this hidden object, which
is a plate for your doughnut. So, have a
look at the shape here that I've got and
have a think about how you would go
about creating this and try to do it
yourself. Just give it a step. Even if
you don't feel confident, you don't feel
like you could uh achieve it, just give
it a go. Um, there's a hint, we've got
some modifiers on the right here. And I
will also show you what the wireframe
looks like. um cuz that will probably
help some people out as well. Okay, so
that's a pretty big hint. Um but yeah,
give a go without any instruction from
me. Have a stab at that. In the next
part, I'll very quickly show you how to
uh how to create this. Um if you're get
completely lost, you can join me in that
part, but please have a go at trying to
do it yourself. Anyway, go ahead, join
me in the next part after you have tried
to create this by